GLOBAL PRODUCT MARKETING MANAGER

Summary

Broad experience in Enterprise Services including hosting, networking/mobility, storage, applications managed security services, enterprise applications [SAP, Oracle], Application Transformation/Application Modernization [AMOD/ATrans], Application Development [ADMS], Application Management [AMS] and Testing and Quality Assurance [TQA] *Demonstrated experience in variety of roles: business development, accounting, costing and pricing, solution consulting, training, event support, product and marketing planning, strategy and execution *Exceptional verbal and written communication skills, with demonstrated ability to effectively engage audiences, deep experience across integrated marketing communication channels *Strengths: Independent self-starter; ability to multi-task in highly energetic, fast-paced, ambiguous environments while keeping everyone inside and outside the company in the loop; a passion for sharing ideas with others; flexible and innovative - can deal with rapid change and enjoys pushing status quo

Highlights

- Global marketing
- Excellent written and verbal communicator
- Enthusiastic team player
- Trade shows

- Start-up background
- Digital advertising
- Pricing strategies
- Presentations

Experience

 $\begin{tabular}{l} Vee am\ October\ 2014\ to\ Current\ Global\ Product\ Marketing\ Manager\ Santa\ Fe\ ,\ NM \end{tabular}$

• Product / Services HP Enterprise Security Services Responsibilities and achievements Created relevant marketing collateral/content and worked with region teams for localization Equipped regional marketing, sales teams, and channel partners with tools and messages for effective product positioning Energized marketing plans with engaging and compelling customer value propositions Ensured crossorganizational alignment by forging strong partnerships with delivery, sales, regional teams and business units to drive marketing success Worked with Security Services practice and delivery to Identify and develop innovative marketing programs Identified/aligned crossfunctional and cross-organizational teams as needed to plan and execute Go-to-Market plans Utilized marketing practices, tactics and tools, created marketing opportunities to bring awareness to HP Managed Security Services Updated, refreshed, and created collateral for new and existing Managed Security services offerings Developed offering facts and analyst ranking database for Practice and sales use Coordinated both Wins and Case Study/Success story information for ES Security, working directly with client executives and reference teams to produce new material for sales use Engaged in weekly meetings with Enterprise Security Practice leaders and CuP team to drive full Enterprise Security Services Content refresh achieving exceptional results Developed marketing content and plans for new offering and product launches, in coordination with regional campaigns.

Identified, developed and evaluated marketing strategies based on knowledge of company objectives and market trends. Collaborated with marketing and communications teams on standardization, design and production of marketing materials. Developed innovative product solutions grounded in clear understanding of customer needs. Partnered with internal stakeholders to define marketing program requirements. Partnered with internal stakeholders to define marketing program requirements.

HP Enterprise Applications January 2010 to January 2014 WW Product Marketing Manager (Various Services) City, STATE

 HP EA Application Transformation Services Product / Services HP Applications Transformation and Modernization Services HP Applications Development Services, Testing and Quality Assurance Services, and Application Management Services Role World Wide Product Marketing Manager, multiple services Responsibilities Managed product marketing budgets and yearly planning for Testing Services, Applications Development Services and Application Management Services; acting interim marketing manager for Applications Transformation and Modernization services Created and executed marketing plans for each offering, handled interlock plans with regional marketing Conducted and leveraged market analysis to establish baseline market awareness developed plans for raising offering preference Created Knowledge Matters assets supporting AMOD, ATrans, ADEV, Testing QA and Apps Management to increase external awareness, successfully influenced clients and analysts Became and accepted authority on technology as it related to industry trends Promoted (marketed HP thought leadership) AMOD, ATrans, ADEV, Testing and Apps Management services via Knowledge Matters program utilizing Social Media and corporate networks; reviewed, edited and promoted Thought Leader content Marketing asset creation/support: variety of iTools, video's, and social media creation for variety of offerings including the "Race to the New Style of IT" promotion Coordination with/participation in, relevant global marketing campaigns Aligned, lead and influenced plans and investments to create end-to-end marketing programs Ensured cross-business unit offering alignment by forging strong partnerships with delivery, regional teams and other business units to drive success Identified/aligned cross-functional and cross-organizational teams as needed to plan and execute Go-to-Market plans Worked with product management teams to develop innovative marketing programs and opportunities for external audience exposure Created engaging and compelling customer value propositions with support of region and product management teams Equipped regional marketing, sales teams, and channel partners with tools and messages for effective product positioning Created, updated, and refreshed marketing collateral for existing services offerings Coordinated both Wins and Case Study/Success story information for, working directly with client executives and reference teams to produce new material for sales use.

EDS/HP ITO Enterprise Services EDS/HP Marketing January 2006 to January 2010 Global Marketing and Sales Readiness Leader City, STATE

• Early adopter of Social Media as marketing tool, one of first EDS/HP Certified Bloggers Supported and influenced strategic plans and investments to create an end-to-end marketing programs Preparation and presentation of sales training materials Product research,

promotion, performance, trending and review analysis preparation for senior executives Market and opportunity analysis Facilitation of new product/offering marketing materials, product training, direct link between delivery and sales teams.

EDS ITO Storage Services January 2004 to January 2006 Delivery Readiness Leader City , STATE

• EDS Enterprise Storage Delivery Product / Services EDS Enterprise Storage Services Role Storage Delivery Readiness Leader - NAS and Enterprise Storage Services Responsibilities Preparation and presentation of sales training materials Product research, promotion, performance, trending and review analysis preparation for senior executives Market and opportunity analysis Facilitation of new product/offering marketing materials, product training, direct link between delivery and sales teams Issue tracking and resolution, project management for new product release Product/Service Line EDS Enterprise Storage Services Role EDS Pricing Catalog Delivery team Responsibilities Facilitation of in-person employee training for EDS pricing catalogue tool at EDS locations around the globe Offering documentation preparation for introduction to EDS Catalogue EDS product pricing determination/validation Issue Tracking and Resolution Product pricing market research and analysis Pre- and post-installation team support.

EDS ITO Web Hosting Services January 2000 to January 2004 Web Hosting Solution Consultant City , STATE

• EDS Web Hosting Business Development Product / Services EDS Web Hosting Services Responsibilities Deal support, including sales enablement, cost and pricing strategy, solution competitive positioning Performed deal pricing, pricing proposals and development of pricing strategies Bid Preparation and Support, worked with sales teams for client consulting Prepared Web Hosting services responses to Request for Proposal (RFP), Request for Information (RFI) and direct sales opportunities Performed requirements analysis, definition, gathering, and verification as well as market analysis research Service promotion (marketing), creation of client marketing materials Pre-Sales support, consulting support, deal team opportunity analysis support Utilized presentation, marketing and sales skills with internal teams and clients to influence client preference for EDS services Highly successful sales support working on multi-million dollar contract wins.

Education

University Of Denver Master Of Arts: International Economic Security International Relations City, State, United States Of America International Economic Security International Relations

Emory And Henry College Bachelor Of Arts: History And Political Science Liberal Arts City, State, United States Of America History And Political Science Liberal Arts

Languages

Language ability in French, basic German and Spanish, learning Scots Gaelic

Affiliations

Associate member: American Marketing Association (AMA) Associate member: ASUG (American SAP Users Group) HTML Guild Fellow, Society of Antiquaries, Scotland "FSA Scot" Continuing Education Project Management Collin County Community College, Plano, Texas HTML Collin County Community College, Plano, Texas Product Management - Cornell School of Business Product Marketing - EDS and HP courses focusing on PLM, ALM and Social Media Marketing

Publications

Published (university) in Historical and Political Science journals *Current Social Media presence for HP Enterprise Services (Twitter, HP Blogs) *Currently publishing blogs covering technology, security and politics

Personal Information

Have worked and performed employee training outside of U.S. (Europe/Australia) Availability / Preferences Availability Status: Available now Has current passport with expiration date 05/2017 Willing to travel up to 25% in order evangelize technologies and solutions with partners, customers and business leaders Will consider TDY assignment Will consider relocation Will consider global assignment - U.K., Eastern Europe, Asia Pac HP Confidential 1 HP Confidential 6

Additional Information

Have worked and performed employee training outside of U.S. (Europe/Australia)

Availability / Preferences Availability Status: Available now Has current passport with expiration date 05/2017

Willing to travel up to 25% in order evangelize technologies and solutions with partners, customers and business leaders

Will consider TDY assignment Will consider relocation Will consider global assignment - U.K., Eastern Europe, Asia Pac HP Confidential

Skills

analyst, basic, budgets, Business Development, Catalog, competitive, consulting, content, client, clients, database, Delivery, direct sales, documentation, employee training, French, functional, German, global marketing, HP, investments, leadership, market analysis, marketing plans, market research and analysis, marketing, Market, marketing collateral, marketing manager, marketing materials, marketing and sales, materials, meetings, Enterprise, NAS, networks, organizational, positioning, Pricing, pricing strategy, pricing strategies, product management, Product Marketing, Product research, project management, promotion, proposals, Proposal, QA, Quality Assurance, requirements analysis, research, RFI, RFP, sales, Sales support, sales training, Spanish, strategic plans, validation, video, Web Hosting